# **Matt Warman**

#### LINKEDIN.COM/IN/MKWARMAN | MKWARMAN.COM

## **PROFILE:**

Full-Stack Software Engineer with a wide range of experience. Premier software quality and innovative problem solving are my top priorities. Every challenge requiring creative and precise solutions is a unique opportunity to learn and improve.

#### **SKILLS**

- Full lifecycle software architecture and engineering: from concept and design through development, testing, deployment, and ongoing support
- Backend technologies including: C#.NET (ASP, Framework, and Core), Node.js, Express, Python, and Java
- Frontend technologies including: TypeScript (JavaScript), React, Angular, and jQuery
- · Database development and optimization, experience with MongoDB, SQL Server, Postgres, and more
- Mobile development using Ionic, Swift (Xcode) and Kotlin (Android Studio)
- Development utilities: AWS, Docker, Jenkins, Octopus, TeamCity, Kibana, DataDog, WinDbg, and more

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER - SPECIALIST, WILQO, REMOTE - OCT 2023-PRESENT

Led multiple projects from concept to handoff and team support as part of the Specialist Team (architects) reporting to Head of Engineering. Developed scalable backend services for efficient data management and distributed processing. Constructed dynamic data flow frameworks to power rich, tenanted, UI feature suites. Implemented CI/CD pipeline steps to ensure reliable and high-quality deployments. Directed feature team projects as architecture team liaison. Mentored via knowledge transfers, development feedback, and 1-on-1 meetings. Worked closely with business leadership to align product goals. Utilized technologies including C# .NET, Azure, Typescript, Javascript, Python, MongoDb, Postgres, and more.

#### SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER, ZEAL, REMOTE - JAN 2023-SEP 2023

Developed payroll API solutions for customer and internal usage using Node.js with Express and Typescript. Built frontend white label solutions to enable rapid customer success and easy use of Zeal's payroll solutions using React and internal UI frameworks. Deployed to AWS using Jenkins and custom pipelines. Designed and developed new feature suites along with product teams to enable customer success and attract new clients.

### SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER, PAYLOCITY, REMOTE - DEC 2018-DEC 2023

Developed time and labor management solutions using C#, React, AngularJS, Less, Ionic, and SQL Server. Implemented CQRS, RESTful microservice, and event-driven processing patterns for scalability. Optimized performance, improved web application UI/UX, and modernized legacy solutions. Performed penetration testing as application security delegate. Triaged incidents using logs, dashboards, and memory dump analysis via WinDbg. Lead development of multiple initiatives and new features. Mentored team members 1-on-1, through knowledge sharing, and via code reviews.

# SOFTWARE ENGINEER, KABBAGE, ATLANTA GA – MAY 2017-DEC 2018

Built and maintained fintech software solutions for the most valuable startup in Georgia. Stabilized platform technologies and microservices written in C#, ASP.NET, and SQL Server. Developed internal management suites written in Python and Angular. Updated and built new full stack applications using AWS, Postgres, C#, .NET Core, Node, Angular, and React.

## SOFTWARE ENGINEER, THE HOME DEPOT, ATLANTA GA - SEP 2015-MAY 2017

Constructed and maintained payment applications written in JavaScript with AngularJS and Redux using Pivotal Cloud Foundry. Replaced legacy Informix 4GL code with RESTful Java Microservices and SQL database integration. Used modern development practices including Agile, XP, TDD, and CI.

#### IT SPECIALIST, POLYMER SOLUTIONS; CHRISTIANSBURG, VA - MAY 2013-AUG 2015

Implemented and maintained computer systems for users and laboratory equipment conducting polymer analysis. Maintained production website, implemented design and security updates. Performed all duties in compliance with FDA Regulations and ISO 17025 (Compliant with ISO 9001).

# **EDUCATION**

Kennesaw State University - Bachelor of Science in Information Technology, 2021